Register of the Paul Myron Anthony Linebarger Papers, 1922-1967
Hoover Institution Archives
Paul Myron Anthony Linebarger Papers,
1922-1967
82115
Linebarger, Paul Myron Anthony, 1913-1966
(33 manuscript boxes, 7 microfilm reels, 1 album box, 2 envelopes (15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Diaries, correspondence, speeches and writings, printed matter, and photographs, relating to political conditions in China and elsewhere in the Far East, and to psychological warfare during and after World War II. Includes microfilm of P. M. A. Linebarger papers at the Hitotsubashi University Library, Tokyo.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1982.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
China--Politics and government--20th century.; East Asia--Politics and government.; Psychological warfare.; World War, 1939-1945--Propaganda.; China.; East Asia.; World War, 1939-1945.; Propaganda.
Biographical Note
1913, July 11 Born, Milwaukee, Wisconsin
1919-1920 Student, Punaho Academy, Honolulu, Hawaii
1920-1922 Student, British Cathedral School, Shanghai, China
1923-1925 Student, Oberealschule, Baden-Baden, Germany
1926 Student, Kaiser Wilhelm School, Shanghai
1930 University of Nanking
1933 A.B., George Washington University, Washington, D.C.
1936 Ph.D., Johns Hopkins University
Married Margaret Snow (divorced 1949)
1930-1936 Private secretary to P.M.W. Linebarger, Legal Adviser to National Government of China, Nanking and Washington, D.C.
1936-1937 Tutor in division of history, government and economics, Harvard University
1937 Author, The Political Doctrines of Sun Yat-sen
1937-1938 Instructor, political science, Duke University
1938 Author, Government in Republican China
1938-1945 Assistant professor
1941 The China of Chiang Kai-shek
1942 Participated in formation of Office of War Information as Far Eastern specialist
1946 Associate professor
1945-1946 Lecturer, School of Advanced International Studies, Johns Hopkins University
1946 Professor of Asiatic Politics
1948 Author, Psychological Warfare
1950 Married Genevieve Collins
1954 Author, Governments and Politics in the Far East
1966, August 6 Died
Linebarger also wrote fiction and science fiction under the pseudonyms: Anthony Bearden, Felix C. Forrest, Carmichael Smith and Cordwainer Smith
Container List
- Diaries, 1924-1950. (Box No. 1.)
  Diaries and travel journals, arranged in chronological order.
  - 1924-1925 (Box 1., Folder 1)
  - 1926 (Folder 2)
  - 1928 (Folder 3)
  - 1929 (Folder 4)
  - 1935 (Folder 5)
  - 1946 (Folder 6)
  - 1950 (Folder 7)
- Biographical File, 1925-1962. (Box No. 2.)
  Biographical sketches, records, memoranda, and clippings related to the career of Paul M.A. Linebarger, arranged by physical form.
  - Biographical data (Box 2., Folder 1)
  - Clippings (Folder 2)
  - Divorce decree (Folder 3)
  - Financial records (Folder 4-5)
  - Identification cards, employment records (Folder 6)
  - Invitations, calling cards (Folder 7)
  - Military service records (Folder 8)
  - Miscellany (Folder 9)
  - Programs (Folder 10)
  - School papers and scrapbook (Folder 11)
  - Souvenirs of trip to Japan, 1951 (Folder 12)
  - Stamp collection list (Folder 13)
  - Travel brochures and itineraries (Folder 14)
- Correspondence, 1930-1967. (Box No. 3-7.)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - General
    - 1930 (Folder 2)
    - 1931 (Folder 3)
    - 1932 (Folder 4)
    - 1933 (Folder 5)
    - 1936 (Folder 6)
    - 1939 (Folder 7)
    - 1941 (Folder 8)
    - 1945 (Folder 9-12)
    - 1946 (Folder 13)
    - 1949 (Folder 14)
    - 1951 (Folder 15)
    - 1952 (Folder 16)
    - 1953 (Folder 17)
    - 1954 (Folder 18)
    - 1955 (Folder 19)
    - 1956 (Box 4., Folder 1)
    - 1957 (Folder 2-3)
    - 1958 (Folder 4)
    - 1959 (Folder 5)
    - 1960 (Folder 6)
    - 1961 (Folder 7)
    - 1962 (Box 5., Folder 1-2)
    - 1963 (Folder 3)
    - 1964 (Folder 4)
    - 1966 (Folder 5)
    - 1967 (Folder 6)
  - Bachmeyer, Karl, 1952 (Folder 7)
  - Benet, William Rose, 1945 (Folder 8)
  - Brookman, David, 1957 (Folder 9)
  - Burden, Major John A., 1945-1946 (Folder 10)
  - Burks, Ardath W., 1952-1953 (Folder 11)
  - Central Intelligence Agency, 1956, 1962 (Folder 12)
  - Chi, C. C., 1952-1953 (Folder 13)
  - Chu, Jane, 1945 (Folder 14)
  - Cole, Taylor, 1945-1946 (Folder 15)
  - Collins, I. J., 1951-1957 (Box 6., Folder 1)
  - Daugherty, William E., 1957 (Folder 2)
  - Djang Chu, 1943-1962 (Folder 3)
  - Eng (?), Horace, 1945-1946 (Folder 4)
  - Evans, Upshur, 1945 (Folder 5)
  - Fairbank, John King, 1953 (Folder 6)
  - Fall, Bernard, 1956 (Folder 7)
  - Glei, W., 1945 (Folder 8)
  - Halsema, James, 1953 (Folder 9)
  - Herter, Christian A., 1957, 1961 (Folder 10)
  - Hocking, William E., 1945 (Folder 11)
  - Hornbeck, Stanley K., 1957, 1963 (Folder 12)
  - Hunter, Edward, 1956 (Folder 13)
  - Isaacs, Harold, 1955 (Folder 14)
  - Jen Pao-yi, 1956 (Folder 15)
  - Kao Ling-pai, 1956-1957 (Folder 16)
  - Kristol, Irving, 1953 (Folder 17)
  - Lattimore, Owen, 1956 (Folder 18)
  - Lindsay, Erica, 1962 (Folder 19)
  - Lindsay, Michael, 1955-1957 (Folder 20)
  - Linebarger, Genevieve C. (Mrs. P.M.A.), 1952 (Folder 21)
  - Linebarger, Johanna Lesley (daughter of P.M.A.), 1956-1962 (Folder 22)
  - Linebarger, Lillian (mother of P.M.A.), 1945-1962 (Box 7., Folder 1)
  - Linebarger, Louise (sister-in-law of P.M.A.), 1962 (Folder 2)
  - Linebarger, Marcia (daughter of P.M.A.), 1957 (Folder 3)
  - Linebarger, Margaret (first wife of P.M.A.), 1936, 1944, 1954 (Folder 4)
  - Linebarger, W. Wentworth, (brother of P.M.A.), 1962 (Folder 5)
  - MacNair, Harley, 1945 (Folder 6)
  - Mandel, Benjamin, 1961 (Folder 7)
  - Montgomery, Nancy, 1935-1936 (Folder 8)
  - The New Republic, 1962 (Folder 9)
  - Price, Maurice T., 1953 (Folder 10)
  - The Psychological Warfare School, 1955-1956 (Folder 11)
  - Rankin, Robert S., 1945-1946 (Folder 12)
  - Relm Foundation, 1962 (Folder 13)
  - Rockefeller Brothers Fund, 1956 (Folder 14)
  - Solbert, General O., 1945, 1956 (Folder 15)
  - Strausz-Hupe, Robert, 1957, 1959 (Folder 16)
  - Tao Hsi-sheng, 1953-1957, 1962 (Folder 17)
  - Tsou, Tang, 1961 (Folder 18)
  - Tu Kwang-hsun, 1961 (Folder 19)
  - Votaw, Professor, 1945 (Folder 20)
  - Walker, Richard L., 1956, 1962 (Folder 21)
  - Wannamaker, William H., 1945-1946 (Folder 22)
  - Wedemeyer, General Albert C., 1945, 1955-1956 (Folder 23)
  - Weyl, Nathaniel, 1957 (Folder 24)
  - Yin Pao-yu (?), 1946 (Folder 25)
- Speeches And Writings, 1930-1966. (Box No. 8-18.)
  Manuscripts, notes, drafts, printed copies of the writings of memoranda, printed matter, reports, charts, arranged alphabetically by topic.
  - Three dictograph recordings of speeches by Paul M.A. Linebarger (Box 8., Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous holograph notes (Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous pages (Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous notes, drafts, parts of manuscripts (Folder 4-6)
  - "A General Statement of the Work and of the Policy of the Chinese Government", typescript, n.d. (Folder 7)
  - Japanese history, carbon copy, n.d. (Folder 8-10)
  - "The Journey of Ching Lai", typescript, n.d. (Folder 11)
  - "Music of the Future", carbon copy, n.d. (Folder 12)
  - The Chinese Nation, printed copies, December 10, 1930; February 4, 1931 (Paul M.A. Linebarger, contributing editor) (Folder 13)
  - "The Biography of Wang Mang", carbon copy, 1931 (Box 9., Folder 1)
  - "The 91st Army of Wei, a Short Epoch-Romance of the Age of Chaos", typescript, 1931 (Folder 2)
  - "An Examination of Examinations", printed copy, The University Hatchet, February 9, 1932 (Folder 3)
  - Various copies of The University Hatchet, edited by Paul M.A. Linebarger, 1932 (Folder 4)
  - "The Philosophy of Chaos", typescript, ca. 1933 (Folder 5)
  - "The Taiping Rebellion", typescript, 1933 (Folder 6)
  - The Fourth Decade, a Magazine of New Writers, (Linebarger's writings in the magazine under the pseudonym, Anthony Bearden) published by P.M.A. Linebarger, printed copies, January and February, 1933; March-April, 1934; Summer, 1934 (Folder 7)
  - Lecture notes, 1935 (Folder 8-9)
  - "The Nationalist Democracy of Sun Yat-sen", typescript, 1935 (Folder 10)
  - "The Political Doctrines of Sun Yat-sen", two printed copies, 1937 (Box 10., Folder 1)
  - "Notes and Opinions", holograph, 1939 (Folder 2)
  - Lecture notes, typescript and holograph, 1939-1940 (Folder 3)
  - "China, Left, Right or Center" (in Chinese), 1940 (Folder 4)
  - "The Japanese Colonel", typescript, 1944 (Folder 5)
  - "Atomsk", typescript, ca. 1948 (Folder 6)
  - "Foreign Governments" (working title), outlines and correspondence, 1948 (Folder 7)
  - Outlines, chapters, typescripts and carbons, (under the pseudonym, Carmichael Smith) ca. 1948 (Folder 8)
  - Psychological Warfare, 1948
    - Advertisements (Folder 9)
    - Copyright (Folder 10)
    - Correspondence (Folder 11)
    - Distribution list (by author) (Box 11., Folder 1)
    - Draft (partial) (Folder 2)
    - Lecture outline for speech at Naval War College on psychological warfare, May l, 1948 (Folder 3)
    - Notes (Folder 4)
    - Preface for Japanese edition (Folder 5)
    - Research materials - bibliography (Folder 6)
    - Reviews (Folder 7)
    - Royalty statements (Folder 8)
    - Table of contents (Folder 9)
  - "The Strategist", outline and correspondence, (under the pseudonym, Felix C. Forrest), ca. 1948 (Folder 10)
  - "The Handbook of Black", typescript and carbon copy, 1950 (Folder 11-12)
  - "Passive Resistance", draft, ca. 1950 (Box 12., Folder 1)
  - "Psychological Warfare", lecture, typescript and printed copy, 1950 (Folder 2-3)
  - Notes and drafts on psychological warfare, 1949-1950 (Folder 4-5)
  - Lecture notes, 1951 (Folder 6)
  - "The Propaganda Terrain of Present Day Europe", Nine Seminar Papers, prepared under the direction of Paul M.A. Linebarger for the Department of State, two mimeographed copies, 1951 (Folder 7-8)
  - "The Communist Psychological Attack", two carbon copies, ca. 1951 (Folder 9)
  - "Outside Pressures on China, 1945-1950", two printed copies, 1951 (Box 13., Folder 1)
  - "Southeast Asia Today", transcript of speech, 1951 (Folder 2)
  - "The Foreign Policy of Communist China", reprint from the SAIS Alumni Review,Spring, 1952 (Folder 3)
  - Outline of speech, America Embassy, Havana, Cuba, 1953 (Folder 4)
  - "The International Juridical Status of the Chief Political Entities of Southeast Asia: 1940-1950" by Genevieve C. Linebarger, carbon copy, ca. 1953 (Folder 5)
  - Lecture notes, 1953 (Folder 6)
  - Far Eastern Governments and Politics, notes, drafts, correspondence, outlines, 1953-1954 (Folder 7-10)
  - "Chinese Culture and the Communist Challenge", three copies (two in Spanish and one in English), typescript and carbon copies, 1954 (Folder 11)
  - Psychological Warfare, two printed advertising brochures; miscellaneous notes; printed copy in Thai, 1954 (Folder 12-13)
  - Notes by Ardath W. Burks on Linebarger's manuscript on Japan, ca. 1954 (Folder 14)
  - "Air Power in the Modern Middle East", two reprints from The Annals of the American Academy of Political and Social Science,May, 1955 (Folder 15)
  - "Ethical Dianetics, The Lay Psychotherapy of Mutual Emotional Aid", (under the pseudonym of Carmichael Smith), carbon copy, ca. 1955 (Folder 16)
  - "The Aftermath of Japanese Colonialism in Southeast Asia" by Genevieve Collins Linebarger, processed copy, 1956 (Folder 17)
  - Bibliography of writings by P.M.A. Linebarger, ca. 1956 (Folder 18)
  - "Notes on General Policy, Some Marginal Comments on U.S. General Policy in Relation to Foreign Affairs", carbon copy, 1956 (Folder 19)
  - Foreign Service Institute, Program listing Paul M.A. Linebarger as speaker, ca. 1957 (Folder 20)
  - "Hong Kong and the British Nanyang", typescript, 1957 (Folder 21)
  - "The Fire Sermon of Gautama Siddhartha", typescript, 1958 (Box 14., Folder 1)
  - "Burmese Government and Politics", interleaved carbon copy, extracted from Southeast Asian Governments and Politics, written with Genevieve Collins Linebarger, 1958 (Folder 2)
  - "Government and Politics in Southeast Asia", drafts and notes; holograph, carbon copies and typescript, 1958 (Folder 3-5)
  - "Government and Politics in Southeast Asia", drafts and notes; holograph, carbon copies and typescript, 1958 (Box 15., Folder 1-5)
  - "Overseas China and Kuomintang Vitality", notes, correspondence, 1956-1958 (Box 16., Folder 1)
  - "Languages and Politics in Southeast Asia", draft, 1958 (Folder 2)
  - "Leaders and Crises in Southeast Asia", notes, outlines, draft, 1958 (Folder 3)
  - "Philippine Government and Politics", interleaved carbon copy, extracted from Southeast Asian Governments and Politics,1958 (Folder 4)
  - "Thai Government and Politics", two interleaved carbon copies, extracted from Southeast Asian Governments and Politics,1958 (Folder 5-6)
  - "Communist China's International Objectives", typescript of speech, March 16, 1960 (Box 17., Folder 1)
  - Outline for book review, typescript, ca. 1960 (Folder 2)
  - "The New Japan in a Troubled Asia", Current History, printed copy, December, 1961 (Folder 3)
  - Indonesian language, notes, research materials, writings by Genevieve Collins Linebarger, 1960-1961 (Folder 4)
  - "The Prediction and Deterrence of Subnuclear War Among Developing Nations", outline, correspondence on research proposal, carbon copy, December, 1962 (Folder 5)
  - "The Republic of China on Taiwan", draft, 1962 (Folder 6)
  - Southeast Asia, research materials, notes; holograph, typescript, carbon copies, printed materials, for articles in the Encyclopedia Britannica, written with Genevieve Collins Linebarger, 1961-1962 (Folder 7-8)
  - Southeast Asia, research materials, notes; holograph, typescript, carbon copies, for articles in the Encyclopedia Britannica,1962-1963 (Box 18., Folder 1-2)
  - "Birds, Far Underground", typescript (under the pseudonym, Cordwainer Smith) ca. 1963 (Folder 3)
  - Galley corrections by Linebarger for Communist Strategies in Asia by A. Doak Barnett, holograph, 1963 (Folder 4)
  - "The Immense Potentiality of Psychological Warfare", carbon copy, 1963 (Folder 5)
  - "Norstrilia", draft, (under the pseudonym, Cordwainer Smith) ca. 1963 (Folder 6-7)
  - "Regional Arms Control Arrangements for Developing Areas", proposal outline and correspondence, 1963 (Folder 8)
  - International Information Policy and Psychological Warfare, bibliography for seminar, 1963-1964 (Box 19., Folder 1)
  - Southeast Asia, research materials, notes; holograph, typescript, carbon copies, for articles in the Encyclopedia Britannica,1963-1964 (Folder 2)
  - "Stability and Progress in the Haitian Republic, 1957-1964", outline and assignment sheet for a group monograph, seminar, 1964-1965 (Folder 3)
  - "Psychological Warfare and Related Operations", outline, notes; typescript, 1964 (Folder 4)
  - "Unconventional Warfare", seminar class roster, notes, outline; typescript, holograph, 1964 (Folder 5)
  - "Konfrontasi: History and Definition" by Dr. Mochtar Aziz, preface and notes by Paul M.A. Linebarger and Genevieve Collins Linebarger, 1965 (Folder 6)
  - "The Menace of Small Wars in Africa and Asia Today", outline, typescript, 1965 (Folder 7)
  - Book reviews for United States Information Agency, correspondence, notes, reviews; holograph, typescripts, carbon copies, 1966 (Folder 8)
  - "International Relations", notes, draft; typescript, holograph notes, 1966 (Folder 9)
- Subject File, 1922-1965. (Box No. 19-31.)
  Correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, reports, charts, arranged alphabetically by topic
  - American Political Science Association, program, 1953 (Box 20., Folder 1)
  - Arabic language. "Modern Literary Arabic", processed copy, 1953 (Folder 2)
  - Asia. "The Study of Far Eastern Politics" by Ardath W. Burks, draft, 1958 (Folder 3)
  - Asian nationalism. Panel discussion at meeting of the American Policial Science Association, 1953 (Folder 4)
  - Borneo. Subcontractor's Monograph, Human Relations Area Files, Inc., 1955 (Folder 5)
  - Burma. Information Bulletin of the Burmese Embassy, May 26, 1952 (Folder 6)
  - China (Box 21.)
    - General (Folder 1)
    - Admission to the United Nations. The Committee of One Million Newsletter with lead article opposing admission of China to the U.N., February 11, 1956 (Folder 2)
    - Army proposal for study of China by Alfred Zee Chang, mimeograph, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Communism. Collection of speeches by George K.C. Yeh in the United States, from September 1954 to February 1955, relating to the People's Republic of China (Folder 4)
    - Confucianism. "The Essence of Confucianism" by Charles J. Finger, 1923 (Folder 5)
    - Economic conditions
      - "The International Development of China" by Sun Yat-sen, 1922, reprint 1953 (Folder 6)
      - "Mainland China in Competitive Coexistence", confidential report to the National Planning Association by A. Doak Barnett, July, 1958 (Folder 7)
    - Foreign relations (Box 22.)
      - Japan. "The Secret of China's Resistance" by K.B. Vaidya, 1943 (Folder 1)
      - Latin America. "'Sugar Coated Bullets' for Latin America" by Shen-Yu Dai, December 23, 1961 (Folder 2)
      - United States (Folder 3-4)
        - "The Centenary Celebration of Sino-American Intellectual Friendship" by Prof. Chang Chi-yun, 1953
        - "Chronological Report of the Student-Interpreter, November 20 Y.R.", by Homer K.M. Wu, 1931 (?)
    - Geography. "Climate and Man in China" by Prof. Chang Chi-yun, 1953 (Folder 5)
    - History. "An Interpretation of The Ancient Chinese Civilization", Chinese Association for the United Nations, Taipei, Taiwan, 1952 (Folder 6)
    - Language in the Peoples Republic of China. Carbon copy of a list, "A Collection of New Terms Used in Communist China", including the original Chinese characters, the romanization of these characters, the literal translations of these words (word by word), and the usage of the term, ca. 1955 (Folder 7)
    - Legal system. "The Law in China as Seen by Roscoe Pound", edited by Tsao Wen-yen, 1953 (Folder 8)
    - Miscellany (Folder 9)
    - Overseas Chinese (Folder 10)
      - "Overseas Chinese - Communist China's First Decade", by Stanley Spector, reprint from The New Leader, June l, 1959
      - "Programs of Communist China for Overseas Chinese", by Lu Yu-Sun, Communist China Problem Research Series, The Union Research Institute, Hong Kong, 1956
      - Project Ultramar, a research proposal concerning certain educational and political aspects of overseas Chinese communities in Southeast Asia, ca. 1954
      - Table of contents for "A Record of the Struggle of the Anti-Communist Returnees from Korea", 1945
    - Politics and government (Folder 11-13)
      - Charts of government organization, in English and Chinese, ca. 1940
      - "Manifesto of the Eighth National Congress of the Kuomintang", 1957
      - "The Political Platform of the Kuomintang", 1957
      - "Theory and Techniques of the Chinese Nationalist Revolution, The Agrarian and Labor Movements" by Ellis Leigh Waldron
    - Psychological warfare (Folder 14)
      - "How Does the CCP Wage Its Psychological War Against the U.S." abridged translation of report in Chinese, n.d.
      - Resume of conversations between the panel on Special Operations and Psychological Warfare of the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Research and Development, Department of Defense, led by Prof. Wilbur Schramm of Stanford University and Chinese psychological warfare experts, n.d.
    - Scientists. "Scientists in Communist China" by Alfred Zee Chang, June 4, 1954 (Folder 15)
    - Shanghai. List of major events in Shanghai, 1949-1951 (Folder 16)
    - Sun Yat-sen. "Memoirs of a Chinese Revolutionary", 1918 (Folder 17)
    - World War II. Office of War Information materials used in China against the Japanese. See Also, Republic Of China (Taiwan) (Folder 18)
  - Chinese language. Romanizations lists (Folder 19)
  - Cold War (Box 23., Folder 1)
    - Papers on Protracted War, 1956-1958, Foreign Policy Research Institute, University of Pennsylvania, 1957
    - "Protracted Conflict", project outline, Foreign Policy Research Institute, 1959 (Folder 2)
  - Communism (Box 24., Folder 1)
    - Memorandum - Communists and Ex-Communists Known to Paul Linebarger Outside the Reported and Proper Conduct of Government Business, 1928-1956, February 26, 1956
    - "A Plan for Counteraction Against Communism Through the Establishment of a Free World Commission and a Free World Academy", Confidential Study Document, Council Against Communist Aggression
  - Congo. Printed materials on the Belgian Congo (Folder 2)
  - Defense Science Board. Roster (Folder 3)
  - Education - government research programs in colleges and universities (Folder 4)
  - Foreign Policy Research Institute, University of Pennsylvania
    - General (Folder 5)
    - Book reviews (Folder 6)
    - Correspondence (Folder 7)
    - Documents (Folder 8)
    - Meeting agendas (Folder 9)
    - Memoranda (Folder 10)
    - Miscellany (Folder 11)
    - Project outlines (Folder 12)
    - Proposals (Folder 13)
    - Writings (Folder 14-16)
      - Miscellaneous chapters, articles
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1955-1958 (Box 25., Folder 1)
  - Guerrilla warfare. Outline for book, 1958 (Box 26., Folder 1)
  - Hurley, Patrick. Article on Hurley, PM, December 4, 1945 (Folder 2)
  - Indonesia.
    - General. "The Potential Giant: Indonesia", carbon copy of manuscript, n.d. (Folder 3)
    - Printed matter
      - Bahasa dan Budaja (incomplete)
        - 1952 (Folder 4)
        - 1953 (Folder 5)
        - 1954 (Folder 6)
        - 1956 (Folder 7)
        - 1957 (Folder 8)
        - 1958 (Box 27., Folder 1)
        - 1959 (Folder 2)
        - 1960 (Folder 3)
      - Miscellaneous printed matter in Indonesian (Folder 4)
  - Insurgency. "The Principles of Insurgency" by Col. Virgil Ney, n.d. (Folder 5)
  - International relations. Bibliography and course outline (Folder 6)
  - Journal of the History of Ideas. Minutes of annual meeting, May 14, 1955 (Folder 7)
  - Korea. "Summation of United States Army Military Government Activities in Korea", Commander-in-Chief, Far East, February, 1947 (Folder 8)
  - Korean language. Romanization charts (Folder 9)
  - Language, universal. "International Auxiliary Language Association in the United States, Outline of Program", 1924 (Folder 10)
  - Manchuria (Folder 11)
    - "Japan's Positive Policy in Manchuria", Memorial presented to His Majesty the Emperor of Japan by Premier Tanaka, outlining the positive policy in Manchuria, n.d.
    - "Manchuria Before November 16", November, 1931
  - Media analysis
    - 1954 (Folder 12)
    - 1955 (Folder 13)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 28., Folder 1)
    - 1960 (Folder 2)
  - Middle East. Studies on the Middle East by the Foreign Policy Research Institute, 1956-1957 (Folder 3)
  - Military operations. Organization charts (Folder 4)
  - Miscellany (Folder 5-6)
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) (Folder 7)
    - Military organization, 1954
    - NATO and Psychological warfare, book outline, 1956